<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Made by Nathan</title>
    <link>https://madebynathan.com/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Made by Nathan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 23:44:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://madebynathan.com/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Keyboard Shortcut: Open a selected file in Sublime Text 2</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2013/03/29/keyboard-shortcut-to-open-selected-file-in-sublime-text-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 23:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2013/03/29/keyboard-shortcut-to-open-selected-file-in-sublime-text-2/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m looking at backtraces, logs, or failing tests in the terminal, I often need to open one of those files in my text editor. It was previously a semi-arduous process that involved highlighting, copying, pasting and the return key. Now, all I need to do is double-click or highlight a line, and then press a keyboard shortcut to open that file &amp;amp; line in my text editor (currently Sublime Text 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>capistrano_colors has been merged into capistrano</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2012/11/08/capistrano_colors-has-been-merged-into-capistrano/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 12:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2012/11/08/capistrano_colors-has-been-merged-into-capistrano/</guid>
      <description>capistrano_colors has been merged into capistrano. If you update capistrano to version 2.13.5, you will no longer need to include capistrano_colors in your Gemfile.Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to also remove require &#39;capistrano_colors&#39; from config/deploy.rb.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve been using capistrano without the capistrano_colors gem, well, you&amp;rsquo;ve been missing out! Your logs will now be nicely formatted and colored by default, like this:
However, if you happen to be a big fan of black &amp;amp; white logs, you can just add disable_log_formatters to config/deploy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto-reloading your .bashrc (or .zshrc)</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2012/10/29/auto-reloading-your-bashrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 20:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2012/10/29/auto-reloading-your-bashrc/</guid>
      <description>If you often make changes to your ~/.bashrc, you might be sick of typing source ~/.bashrc after every change. It can also be annoying when you switch to a different tab in your terminal, but your new aliases or functions aren&amp;rsquo;t available until you type source ~/.bashrc.
While I was working on scm_breeze and my dotfiles repo, I grew tired of having to type this command, so I aliased it to sbrc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving space in the terminal with symbols</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2012/10/14/saving-space-in-the-terminal-with-symbols/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 22:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2012/10/14/saving-space-in-the-terminal-with-symbols/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m saving a little space in my terminal by replacing my username and group (ndbroadbent) with a single symbol. I&amp;rsquo;m doing this in my prompt, as well as in the output of ls commands:
(My laptop&amp;rsquo;s hostname is also represented by a symbol.)
For the ls output, it was a bit tricky to re-justify the username and group columns after substituting my username. I decided to do it in ruby, and then played some ruby golf:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skype notifications using libnotify on Linux</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2012/03/24/skype-notifications-using-libnotify-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 18:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2012/03/24/skype-notifications-using-libnotify-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>Skype on Linux comes with it&amp;rsquo;s own notification system. It&amp;rsquo;s not that bad, but it&amp;rsquo;s not consistent, either. If you want to configure Skype to use libnotify instead, run the following script in your terminal:
(NOTE: You must have installed Skype, and logged in at least once.)
bash &amp;lt; &amp;lt;(curl -s https://raw.github.com/gist/2181122/skype-libnotify.sh) This downloads and executes the script from this gist: https://gist.github.com/2181122
It fetches the skype configuration from here, which is part of my dotfiles repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling one-off tasks with &#39;at&#39;</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2012/02/25/scheduling-one-off-tasks-with-at-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2012/02/25/scheduling-one-off-tasks-with-at-/</guid>
      <description>You might be familiar with the cron job scheduler, which is great for repeating tasks. But when you want to schedule a command to only run once in the future, the at command is what you are looking for.
In my case, I was updating a plugin for our Thoughtworks Mingle instance, but the update wasn&amp;rsquo;t hugely important. Many of our staff rely on Mingle for their work, and restarting it takes it offline for a few minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A better way to use xclip (clipboard from the command line)</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2011/10/04/a-nicer-way-to-use-xclip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 16:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2011/10/04/a-nicer-way-to-use-xclip/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you just want to copy something from your terminal and paste it somewhere else. You might have heard of a Linux program called xclip, which provides a command line interface to X selections. However, xclip&amp;rsquo;s default selection isn&amp;rsquo;t the clipboard, and typing xclip -selection c -i ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub is just a bit tedious.
So here&amp;rsquo;s a wrapper function that makes it less of a hassle to integrate the clipboard with the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Notifier</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2011/03/19/weather-notifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 15:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2011/03/19/weather-notifier/</guid>
      <description>This is just a little idea I had on the bus.
Outside my apartment, I have a bucket for umbrellas.
A program checks the local weather on weather.com from time to time. If there&#39;s any chance of rain, it switches on the lights installed in the bucket.
So when I walk out the door, I know whether or not I should take an umbrella to work.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RFID apartment lock (&amp; iPhone app)</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/11/05/octopus-card-door-lock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 20:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/11/05/octopus-card-door-lock/</guid>
      <description>Octopus cards in Hong Kong can be used to purchase almost anything, such as groceries, McDonalds, and public transport. Since everyone has one, a lot of apartments are using them for access control.
One of my first projects after moving back to Hong Kong was installing an electronic lock on my apartment door. My door can be now be unlocked with an Octopus RFID card, iPhone app, or over the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm on embedded systems</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/06/26/last-fm-on-embedded-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/06/26/last-fm-on-embedded-systems/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finished most of the work I&amp;rsquo;m going to do on my shell.fm ruby server. Its written on sinatra + jquery + jquery-ui (so, a lot of ajax calls). It also requires my custom shell.fm fork if you want the volume control to work.
You can find my shell.fm fork here: http://github.com/ndbroadbent/shell-fm
and the shell.fm sinatra server is here: http://github.com/ndbroadbent/shell-fm_sinatra
By the way, this post is about an embedded linux system that plays last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm Player - Project Videos</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/project-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 11:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/project-videos/</guid>
      <description>My Compaq Evo T20 running tinycore linux, playing shell.fm, displaying track info via lcd4linux on a Pertelian X2o40 USB LCD display.

 
Uses music software Reaper to play audio and generate MIDI events. Midi events are sent to the &#39;output&#39; of MIDI Yoke, which patches them to a software emulated MIDI input. Used the MIDIOX COM wrapper with Visual Basic, to monitor the MIDI Yoke input and trigger http downloads on certain MIDI note events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use a bluetooth headset on Ubuntu 9.10 &#43;</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/how-to-use-a-bluetooth-headset-on-ubuntu-9-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 10:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/how-to-use-a-bluetooth-headset-on-ubuntu-9-10/</guid>
      <description>I found a little bluetooth headset at work, and wanted to play audio through it from my laptop. It turns out that nowadays, Ubuntu actually makes this really easy.
I found a guide written for Ubuntu 9.04 on this forum post, but Ubuntu 9.10 now does most of the work for you. (Steps 15 through 27 are still used in this guide, so credit to HyRax1 from forums.overclockers.com.au for the original tutorial)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pertelian X2040, lcd4linux, shell-fm</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/20/pertelian-x2040-lcd4linux-shell-fm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 13:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/20/pertelian-x2040-lcd4linux-shell-fm/</guid>
      <description>I received my Pertelian X2040, and had a bit of trouble getting it work on my 64bit Ubuntu machine. The characters were getting all mixed up. I gave up on my 64bit machine and decided to focus my efforts on the T20 running tinycore.
To get lcd4linux running on tinycore with any lcd screen, you need the dbus, usbutils and usb-serial packages installed.
At first, lcd4linux was asking me for mysql, and then sqlite, and those are pretty hefty packages for a little thin client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Compaq Evo T20 works</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/15/it-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 22:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/15/it-works/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finished the software research stage of my Compaq Evo T20 experiments. I have settled on the Tinycore 2.7 distribution. So I now have a 300MHz thin client that:
 can connect to a wired or wireless network. can play audio through its onboard sound device. has the required libraries to run MPD (music player daemon) and shell.fm (minimal console application for streaming last.fm stations.) can run Ruby 1.8.7, rubygems, rails, sinatra, etc (Ruby 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compaq Evo T20 projects</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/08/compaq-evo-t20-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 13:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/08/compaq-evo-t20-projects/</guid>
      <description>Compaq Evo T20s are fun. I have a few that I&amp;rsquo;m using for various projects. I plan to set one up as a RFID controlled alarm/door lock system. Its running Damn Small Linux using ruby, rubygems and sinatra packages that I compiled myself.
Karl Mowatt-Wilson&amp;rsquo;s tutorials have been a huge help with flashing the T20s with linux images, as well as the open-evot20 site.
I wrote a K8055 USB Ruby C wrapper for the K8055 USB interface experiment board (bought from here).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>