<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Nathan Broadbent</title>
    <link>http://madebynathan.com/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Nathan Broadbent</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 19:07:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://madebynathan.com/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Grooveshark - Set Current Song as Browser Title</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/11/04/grooveshark-set-current-song-as-browser-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 19:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/11/04/grooveshark-set-current-song-as-browser-title/</guid>
      <description>I like Grooveshark. Its like last.fm, but you can choose the songs &amp;amp; albums you want to play. I would like to get a subscription one day, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure when the RIAA is planning their attack, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll hold off for now :)
In the meantime, I was dissapointed that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see which song was currently playing in the browser title. So heres a greasemonkey script to do just that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm on embedded systems</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/06/26/last-fm-on-embedded-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/06/26/last-fm-on-embedded-systems/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finished most of the work I&amp;rsquo;m going to do on my shell.fm ruby server. Its written on sinatra + jquery + jquery-ui (so, a lot of ajax calls). It also requires my custom shell.fm fork if you want the volume control to work.
You can find my shell.fm fork here: http://github.com/ndbroadbent/shell-fm
and the shell.fm sinatra server is here: http://github.com/ndbroadbent/shell-fm_sinatra
By the way, this post is about an embedded linux system that plays last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm Player - Project Videos</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/project-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 11:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/project-videos/</guid>
      <description>My Compaq Evo T20 running tinycore linux, playing shell.fm, displaying track info via lcd4linux on a Pertelian X2o40 USB LCD display.

 
Uses music software Reaper to play audio and generate MIDI events. Midi events are sent to the &#39;output&#39; of MIDI Yoke, which patches them to a software emulated MIDI input. Used the MIDIOX COM wrapper with Visual Basic, to monitor the MIDI Yoke input and trigger http downloads on certain MIDI note events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fireworks display in time to music.</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/25/fireworks-display-in-time-to-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 14:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/25/fireworks-display-in-time-to-music/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a REAPER license for a year or 2 now. Get rid of Logic Pro and Protools, REAPER is the most awesome music creation software I have ever used. I love the unparalleled flexibility to make it do whatever you can imagine.
I just followed this extremely helpful tutorial by Dave Hayes  to get REAPER running on Ubuntu with wineasio. And now, I am in the middle of researching midi plugins that can trigger shell or network events.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>