<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Made by Nathan</title>
    <link>http://madebynathan.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Made by Nathan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 23:51:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://madebynathan.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Microwave</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2013/07/10/raspberry-pi-powered-microwave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 23:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2013/07/10/raspberry-pi-powered-microwave/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, I was inspired by this post on Reddit, titled: Food items should have QR codes that instruct the microwave exactly what to do. Like high for 2 minutes, let stand 1 minute, medium 1 minutes..
I thought this was a pretty cool idea, and that it would be a fun project for a Raspberry Pi. I agreed with the people who thought using UPC barcodes would be better, since products already have them, so I went with a barcode scanner + online product database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ubuntu Keyboard Shortcut: Open a selected file in Sublime Text 2</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2013/03/29/keyboard-shortcut-to-open-selected-file-in-sublime-text-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2013 23:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2013/03/29/keyboard-shortcut-to-open-selected-file-in-sublime-text-2/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m looking at backtraces, logs, or failing tests in the terminal, I often need to open one of those files in my text editor. It was previously a semi-arduous process that involved highlighting, copying, pasting and the return key. Now, all I need to do is double-click or highlight a line, and then press a keyboard shortcut to open that file &amp;amp; line in my text editor (currently Sublime Text 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open files generated by &#39;rails generate&#39; in your editor</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/12/20/open-files-generated-by-rails-generate-in-your-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 13:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/12/20/open-files-generated-by-rails-generate-in-your-editor/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post is for people who use the terminal to run Rails generators. It probably won&amp;rsquo;t interest you if your editor has a plugin to run them. 
After running a Rails generator, you&amp;rsquo;ll often need to edit the generated files in your text editor.
Rails 4 may soon have the ability to open generated files in your text editor if you pass the --editor option on the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically run &#39;bundle install&#39; when Bundler can&#39;t find a gem</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/12/18/automatically-run-bundle-install-if-bundler-raises-gemnotfound/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 19:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/12/18/automatically-run-bundle-install-if-bundler-raises-gemnotfound/</guid>
      <description>Every Rails developer has probably experienced the following error:
Could not find &amp;lt;gem&amp;gt; in any of the sources Run `bundle install` to install missing gems.   This happens if you or someone else adds a gem to your Gemfile, or if a gem version is updated in Gemfile.lock, and you forget to run bundle install before running a Rails command.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple function that handles this automatically, called bundle_install_wrapper().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>capistrano_colors has been merged into capistrano</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/11/08/capistrano_colors-has-been-merged-into-capistrano/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 12:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/11/08/capistrano_colors-has-been-merged-into-capistrano/</guid>
      <description>capistrano_colors has been merged into capistrano. If you update capistrano to version 2.13.5, you will no longer need to include capistrano_colors in your Gemfile.Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to also remove require &#39;capistrano_colors&#39; from config/deploy.rb.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve been using capistrano without the capistrano_colors gem, well, you&amp;rsquo;ve been missing out! Your logs will now be nicely formatted and colored by default, like this:
However, if you happen to be a big fan of black &amp;amp; white logs, you can just add disable_log_formatters to config/deploy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto-reloading your .bashrc (or .zshrc)</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/10/29/auto-reloading-your-bashrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2012 20:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/10/29/auto-reloading-your-bashrc/</guid>
      <description>If you often make changes to your ~/.bashrc, you might be sick of typing source ~/.bashrc after every change. It can also be annoying when you switch to a different tab in your terminal, but your new aliases or functions aren&amp;rsquo;t available until you type source ~/.bashrc.
While I was working on scm_breeze and my dotfiles repo, I grew tired of having to type this command, so I aliased it to sbrc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving space in the terminal with symbols</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/10/14/saving-space-in-the-terminal-with-symbols/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 22:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/10/14/saving-space-in-the-terminal-with-symbols/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m saving a little space in my terminal by replacing my username and group (ndbroadbent) with a single symbol. I&amp;rsquo;m doing this in my prompt, as well as in the output of ls commands:
(My laptop&amp;rsquo;s hostname is also represented by a symbol.)
For the ls output, it was a bit tricky to re-justify the username and group columns after substituting my username. I decided to do it in ruby, and then played some ruby golf:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate your Rails development with cron: Keep projects updated, install gems, and maintain a repo index</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/10/11/automate-your-development-machine-keep-projects-updated-install-gems-refresh-git-repo-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 14:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/10/11/automate-your-development-machine-keep-projects-updated-install-gems-refresh-git-repo-index/</guid>
      <description>A day in the life of a Rails developer will usually involve a few git pulls, bundle installs, and switching between different projects. I thought it would be great if my projects could be automatically kept up-to-date, so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to spend too much time updating code or installing new gems.
I&amp;rsquo;m using the whenever gem to create cron tasks that:
 Update all my git repos from their remotes Satisfy all of my Gemfile&amp;rsquo;s dependencies Cache rake and capistrano commands for tab completion Fetch Travis CI build statuses to show in my terminal Maintain an index of my git repos so I can quickly switch between projects, while keeping them organized  For all of these tasks, I&amp;rsquo;m using the git_index function provided by my SCM Breeze project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to start a Google Group for a git project</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/09/19/how-to-start-a-google-group-for-a-git-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 12:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/09/19/how-to-start-a-google-group-for-a-git-project/</guid>
      <description>GitHub is a great way to manage code for an open source project, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide any way to send a message to all of your watchers. This can be necessary whenever you make certain changes to your application. For example, I recently merged a pull request in Errbit that requires users to run a Rake task next time they update the code. I had no way of notifying our users, so I decided to create a Google Group mailing list for these kinds of notifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skype notifications using libnotify on Linux</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/03/24/skype-notifications-using-libnotify-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 18:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/03/24/skype-notifications-using-libnotify-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>Skype on Linux comes with it&amp;rsquo;s own notification system. It&amp;rsquo;s not that bad, but it&amp;rsquo;s not consistent, either. If you want to configure Skype to use libnotify instead, run the following script in your terminal:
(NOTE: You must have installed Skype, and logged in at least once.)
bash &amp;lt; &amp;lt;(curl -s https://raw.github.com/gist/2181122/skype-libnotify.sh)  This downloads and executes the script from this gist: https://gist.github.com/2181122
It fetches the skype configuration from here, which is part of my dotfiles repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling one-off tasks with &#39;at&#39;</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/02/25/scheduling-one-off-tasks-with-at-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/02/25/scheduling-one-off-tasks-with-at-/</guid>
      <description>You might be familiar with the cron job scheduler, which is great for repeating tasks. But when you want to schedule a command to only run once in the future, the at command is what you are looking for.
In my case, I was updating a plugin for our Thoughtworks Mingle instance, but the update wasn&amp;rsquo;t hugely important. Many of our staff rely on Mingle for their work, and restarting it takes it offline for a few minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travis CI Status in Shell Prompt</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/01/14/travis-ci-status-in-shell-prompt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2012 01:21:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/01/14/travis-ci-status-in-shell-prompt/</guid>
      <description>Update: I&amp;rsquo;ve updated the build status checking script, because updating all branches was taking too long (over 20 minutes.) Now it performs frequent updates for the current branch, and only periodic updates for all branches.
Travis CI is a distributed continuous integration service for the open source community, and it can be used with any of your public projects on GitHub. You&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen some &amp;lsquo;build status&amp;rsquo; badges like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Multiple Databases for a Rails app on Travis CI</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/12/13/testing-multiple-databases-for-a-rails-app-on-travis-ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 23:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/12/13/testing-multiple-databases-for-a-rails-app-on-travis-ci/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing a lot of work on an open source Ruby on Rails project called Fat Free CRM. The code is hosted on github, and we are using the amazing continuous integration service provided by Travis CI.
Find out more about Travis CI here.
We&amp;rsquo;ve been working on some powerful features for Fat Free CRM, such as dynamic custom fields, and we wanted to make sure that they work across all of our supported databases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Project Design Assets For Git Repositories: A Simple Solution</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/10/21/managing-project-design-assets-for-git-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 23:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/10/21/managing-project-design-assets-for-git-repositories/</guid>
      <description>When you&amp;rsquo;re creating logos or icons for a project that uses git, have you ever wondered where you should store those .psd or .xcf files? Do you commit all of your raw design files, or does it put you off that any changes to those files will bloat your repository?
The following post describes a part of my SCM Breeze project. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen it already, take a look at my blog post that describes what it can do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Reasons why Hackers should Jailbreak their iPhones</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/10/20/10-reasons-why-hackers-should-jailbreak-their-iphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 18:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/10/20/10-reasons-why-hackers-should-jailbreak-their-iphones/</guid>
      <description>There was a post on the front page of Hacker News recently, titled &amp;ldquo;Making Chrome better on iOS&amp;rdquo;. Google&amp;rsquo;s Chrome browser is now available on iOS, and the author of the article was talking about how app developers could be persuaded to add some code to their apps which would allow Chrome to open links.
Restrictions like this (not being able to change your default browser) are one of the many reasons why I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t buy another iPhone if it couldn&amp;rsquo;t be jailbroken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Shortcuts Like You&#39;ve Never Seen Before</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/10/19/git-shortcuts-like-youve-never-seen-before/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 01:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/10/19/git-shortcuts-like-youve-never-seen-before/</guid>
      <description>Introducing &amp;lsquo;SCM Breeze&amp;rsquo; SCM Breeze is a set of shell scripts (for bash and zsh) that enhance your interaction with tools such as git. It integrates with your shell to give you numbered file shortcuts, a repository index with tab completion, and a community driven collection of useful SCM functions.
Disclaimer: git is currently the only supported SCM. I&amp;rsquo;ve kept the project&amp;rsquo;s name open because it won&amp;rsquo;t be difficult to port it for other SCMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A better way to use xclip (clipboard from the command line)</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/10/04/a-nicer-way-to-use-xclip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 16:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/10/04/a-nicer-way-to-use-xclip/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you just want to copy something from your terminal and paste it somewhere else. You might have heard of a Linux program called xclip, which provides a command line interface to X selections. However, xclip&amp;rsquo;s default selection isn&amp;rsquo;t the clipboard, and typing xclip -selection c -i ~/.ssh/id_rsa.pub is just a bit tedious.
So here&amp;rsquo;s a wrapper function that makes it less of a hassle to integrate the clipboard with the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t use &#39;bundle install {gem}&#39;.</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/09/03/dont-use-bundle-install-gem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 04:39:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/09/03/dont-use-bundle-install-gem/</guid>
      <description>Maybe you want to update haml to the latest version. You tried to run bundle install haml, but now some really weird stuff is happening. Bundler decided to install all of your gems from scratch into a ./haml folder. Even when you try bundle update haml, the gems are still going into the ./haml folder! What&amp;rsquo;s going on?
bundle install haml is totally different from bundle update haml.
What bundle install haml does:  Installs all of your gems into a &amp;lsquo;haml&amp;rsquo; folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running bash color codes through sed</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/08/18/running-bash-color-codes-through-sed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2011 04:48:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/08/18/running-bash-color-codes-through-sed/</guid>
      <description>I have a script that runs a search and replace on a git status. I recently found out how to do &#39;git config color.status always&#39;, so that git status gives color codes to my functions. However, this broke the substitution, and it took me a while to figure it out.
At the end of every line, there was an invisible &#39;reset&#39; color code, and this meant that &#39;sed &#34;s/string$/$replace&#34;&#39; was no longer finding &#39;string$&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash Color Index</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/08/16/bash-color-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 08:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/08/16/bash-color-index/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s nice to add color output to your bash scripts. Here&amp;rsquo;s a small &amp;lsquo;color index&amp;rsquo; reference script for your .bashrc, for when you want to add a bit of color to your scripts.
Save the following script somewhere in your PATH (e.g. /bin/color_index), and make it executable. (chmod +x /bin/color_index)
#!/bin/bash # Bash Colors Index # Shows an index of all available bash colors # ------------------------------------------------ echo -e &amp;quot;\n Usage: \\\e[*;**(;**)m&amp;quot; echo -e &amp;quot; Default: \\\e[0m&amp;quot; blank_line=&amp;quot;\e[0m\n \e[0;30;40m$(printf &amp;quot;%41s&amp;quot;)\e[0m&amp;quot; echo -e &amp;quot;$blank_line&amp;quot; # Top border for style in 2 0 1 4 9; do echo -en &amp;quot; \e[0;30;40m &amp;quot; # Display black fg on white bg echo -en &amp;quot;\e[${style};30;47m${style};30\e[0;30;40m &amp;quot; for foreground in $(seq 31 37); do ctrl=&amp;quot;\e[${style};${foreground};40m&amp;quot; echo -en &amp;quot;${ctrl}&amp;quot; echo -en &amp;quot;${style};${foreground}\e[0;30;40m &amp;quot; done echo -e &amp;quot;$blank_line&amp;quot; # Separators done echo -en &amp;quot; \e[0;30;40m &amp;quot; # Background colors echo -en &amp;quot;\e[0;37;40m*;40\e[0;30;40m \e[0m&amp;quot; # Display white fg on black bg for background in $(seq 41 47); do ctrl=&amp;quot;\e[0;30;${background}m&amp;quot; echo -en &amp;quot;${ctrl}&amp;quot; echo -en &amp;quot;*;${background}\e[0;30;40m &amp;quot; done echo -e &amp;quot;$blank_line&amp;quot; &amp;quot;\n&amp;quot; # Bottom border  Running &amp;lsquo;color_index&amp;rsquo; will display something like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically change iPhone wallpaper every 30 minutes</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/07/20/automatically-change-iphone-wallpaper-every-30-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 16:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/07/20/automatically-change-iphone-wallpaper-every-30-minutes/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: This is only for jailbroken iPhones.
I love finding awesome wallpapers on reddit. My Ubuntu desktop cycles through my wallpaper collection with a program called Cortina, and I wanted my iPhone to do the same.
So I wrote a very simple script and a launchd plist that runs the script every 30 minutes. If you want to set this up for your jailbroken iPhone, all you need is SSH and a collection of images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repurposed pressure gauge - Bathroom door indicator</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/04/30/repurposed-pressure-gauge-as-bathroom-indicator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 15:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/04/30/repurposed-pressure-gauge-as-bathroom-indicator/</guid>
      <description>I turned an old brass pressure gauge into a vacant/engaged indicator for our bathroom. The needle is a hacked ammeter, and the metal slide lock on the other side of the door switches it on.
Inspired by this guy&amp;rsquo;s work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Really handy RVM hook to symlink current gem directory</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/04/28/really-handy-rvm-hook-to-symlink-current-gem-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2011 05:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/04/28/really-handy-rvm-hook-to-symlink-current-gem-directory/</guid>
      <description>I use gedit to write code. I keep a filebrowser tab open at the left side of my screen, and sometimes I need to look at gem&amp;rsquo;s source code. RVM is awesome, and it keeps my 1.8.7 gems, 1.9.2 gems and all my gemsets separated, but this makes it tricky to find the gem you need to look at.
Enter RVM hooks! If you want a symlink to the current gem directory to be updated each time you switch ruby versions, save something like the following code to ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avatar Harmony - Sync your profile pics</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/04/25/avatar-harmony-sync-your-profile-pics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 17:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/04/25/avatar-harmony-sync-your-profile-pics/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a tiny web application called &amp;lsquo;Avatar Harmony&amp;rsquo;.
You can sign in with twitter or facebook, add your Gravatar login details, and the app will automatically sync your profile pics across each of your accounts.
It can sync avatars in the following directions:
 Facebook =&amp;gt; Twitter Facebook =&amp;gt; Gravatar Twitter =&amp;gt; Gravatar Gravatar =&amp;gt; Twitter  Unfortunately, the Facebook Graph API doesn&#39;t let us update profile pics at the moment, but I&#39;ll keep looking around for a solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to calculate Easter Sunday</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/03/31/how-to-calculate-easter-sunday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 17:41:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/03/31/how-to-calculate-easter-sunday/</guid>
      <description>I wanted the LCD screen on my apartment door to display a message on certain days, such as birthdays, Christmas, and Easter. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize how hard it was to calculate which day Easter Sunday is&amp;hellip;
def easter(year) c=year/100 n=year-19*(year/19) k=(c-17)/25 i=c-c/4-(c-k)/3+19*n+15 i-=30*(i/30) i-=(i/28)*(1 -(i/28)*(29/(i+1))*((21-n)/11)) j=year+year/4+i+2-c+c/4 j-=7*(j/7) l=i-j month=3+(l+40)/44 day=l+28-31*(month/4) [day, month] end  This happens to be the first Sunday after the Paschal full moon following the northern hemisphere&amp;rsquo;s vernal equinox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Notifier</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/03/19/weather-notifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 15:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/03/19/weather-notifier/</guid>
      <description>This is just a little idea I had on the bus.
Outside my apartment, I have a bucket for umbrellas.
A program checks the local weather on weather.com from time to time. If there&#39;s any chance of rain, it switches on the lights installed in the bucket.
So when I walk out the door, I know whether or not I should take an umbrella to work.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capistrano task - show deployed revisions &amp; diffs</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/03/02/capistrano-task-show-deployed-revisions-diffs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2011 05:43:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/03/02/capistrano-task-show-deployed-revisions-diffs/</guid>
      <description>Capistrano is a great tool, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine running a project without it. I always wanted a quick way to know exactly what was running on each of our servers, and needed to know what would would change when I ran &amp;lsquo;cap deploy&amp;rsquo;.
&amp;ldquo;cap deploy:pending&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;cap deploy:pending:diff&amp;rdquo; already solve this problem a little bit, but I found them to be too verbose. Also, they don&amp;rsquo;t work so well as part of an automated deploy process since they can require user interaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails 3 Rake tasks can take too long to load</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/02/24/rails-3-rake-tasks-are-so-slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 05:02:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/02/24/rails-3-rake-tasks-are-so-slow/</guid>
      <description>When you run a rake task for a Rails 3 project, it has to load the entire environment since gems can include their own rake tasks. I started to get annoyed by this, because every capistrano deployment would load up rails on my environment just to notify hoptoad.
If you have a very simple rake task that is called very often, you might want to add some work-around code to check for it in the very beginning of your Rakefile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails 3 caching views in development mode</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/02/10/rails3-is-caching-views-in-development-mode-but-i-told-it-not-to/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 03:40:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/02/10/rails3-is-caching-views-in-development-mode-but-i-told-it-not-to/</guid>
      <description>We are working with a Rails 3 port of Fat Free CRM. We have so many plugins modifying classes that we have to set config.cache_classes to true. But all our view templates seemed to stay cached as well, and I had to restart the server each time I made a change to a template. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really explain why this was happening, and after a lot of searching I came across this Rails LightHouse ticket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Cydia Themes (Sounds)</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/02/10/new-cydia-themes-sounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2011 01:28:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/02/10/new-cydia-themes-sounds/</guid>
      <description>Custom sounds for iPhone mail tone and keypad I&amp;rsquo;ve released a few small packages to the modmyi cydia repo. You can find them by searching for them by name: 
Message For Me – IT Crowd Mail Tone Replaces the &amp;lsquo;new email&amp;rsquo; sound with a clip of Moss saying &amp;ldquo;Message for me!&amp;rdquo; Overall Downloads:  Piano DTMF Tones Replaces the keypad sounds in the &amp;lsquo;phone&amp;rsquo; app with piano notes. Overall Downloads:  Plants Vs Zombies - Coin SMS Tone Plants Vs Zombies Coin SMS Tone Overall Downloads:  Crash Bandicoot Sounds Replaces iPhone sounds with sounds from the game &amp;ldquo;Crash Bandicoot&amp;rdquo; on Playstation 1  SMS Tone - &amp;lsquo;Ka-ching&amp;rsquo; New Mail Tone - &amp;lsquo;Ooogabooga&amp;rsquo; Sent mail - &amp;lsquo;Spinning noise&amp;rsquo; Plug in to power source - &amp;lsquo;Wumpa fruit&amp;rsquo; Error/low power - &amp;lsquo;TNT&amp;rsquo;  Overall Downloads:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Calvin &amp; Hobbes RSS feed (with embedded images)</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/01/29/daily-calvin-hobbes-rss-feed-with-embedded-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 08:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/01/29/daily-calvin-hobbes-rss-feed-with-embedded-images/</guid>
      <description>Yahoo Pipes is fantastic. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a big fan of yahoo in the past, but their pipes service is amazing. Its great for sprucing up a not-so-well implemented RSS feed, and lets you create feeds from virtually anything on the web.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a daily Calvin and Hobbes RSS feed that parses the comic image from the linked page, and drops it in the feed itself. Perfect for Google Reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a ruby gem and host it on rubygems.org in 4 easy steps</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/01/22/how-to-build-a-ruby-gem-and-host-it-on-rubygems-org-in-4-easy-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 06:39:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/01/22/how-to-build-a-ruby-gem-and-host-it-on-rubygems-org-in-4-easy-steps/</guid>
      <description>Building a ruby gem these days is really, really easy. Bundler provides a great framework generator to get you started. Bundler also lets you install a gem straight from a github repository, so now is the time to say goodbye to your git submodules and start packaging your code into gems.  Sign up for a rubygems.org account $ bundle gem shiny_new_gem (This creates the framework for your gem) Edit &amp;lsquo;shiny_new_gem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add .bashrc to iPhone for SSH or MobileTerminal</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2011/01/07/add-bashrc-to-iphone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2011 07:23:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2011/01/07/add-bashrc-to-iphone/</guid>
      <description>When you SSH into your iPhone, or if you use MobileTerminal, you might want to use some of the aliases or functions that you&amp;rsquo;re used to.
To do this:  Create and edit your &amp;ldquo;.bashrc&amp;rdquo; file at &amp;ldquo;/var/root/.bashrc&amp;rdquo; Add the following line to &amp;ldquo;/etc/profile&amp;rdquo;: 
source /var/root/.bashrc  An example alias would be: alias respring=&amp;ldquo;killall SpringBoard&amp;rdquo;
Colored prompts look great in MobileTerminal too.
This is the bashrc that I use on my iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wikipedia is great, help keep it free!</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/12/31/wikipedia-is-great/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2010 07:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/12/31/wikipedia-is-great/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://wikimediafoundation.org/wiki/Support_Wikipedia/en&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Support Wikipedia&#34; src=&#34;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/41/Fundraising_2009-horizontal-thanks-en.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo iPhone app - Apartment automation</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/12/28/demo-iphone-app-apartment-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 18:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/12/28/demo-iphone-app-apartment-automation/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/ndbroadbent/ios_flat_10c
This is the little app I wrote to control my apartment. Its not going to be much use to anyone by itself, but as it says on the github page:
You could use this as a demo app to help you learn about:  InAppSettingsKit  Configure settings from within an iPhone app.   ASI HTTP library  Sending HTTP GET and POST requests with form data.   Cloning the ‘slide to unlock’ feature from the iPhone lock screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More home automation..</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/12/27/more-home-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 16:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/12/27/more-home-automation/</guid>
      <description>My hall light turns on for 15 minutes if it&amp;rsquo;s past 10pm and I unlock my door with an octopus card or iPhone.

Its just a 12v relay (rated at 240V/30A), and some cat-5 to the thin client PC. All happens to fit perfectly inside the light switch.
Next up, automatic plant watering &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS JB tweak - Replace operator with current prepaid balance</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/12/26/ios-tweak-replace-operator-with-current-prepaid-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2010 16:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/12/26/ios-tweak-replace-operator-with-current-prepaid-balance/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/ndbroadbent/ios_replace_operator_with_balance
Replace Operator on jailbroken iOS 4.x with current prepaid balance. Specifically written for PCCW in Hong Kong, with an AT+CUSD command of “##122#”.
An extension to Fake-Operator
Credit to this site for the source code of sendmodem.
Install
Download the .deb package from the ‘Downloads’ page on github, and install with $ dpkg -i &amp;lt;&amp;lt; package &amp;gt;&amp;gt;.deb
How it works
Package contains an executable binary that sends an AT USSD command to the carrier, which returns the balance message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gedit plugin I18n Helper for Rails</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/12/03/gedit-plugin-i18n-helper-for-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2010 04:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/12/03/gedit-plugin-i18n-helper-for-rails/</guid>
      <description>Gedit plugin - I18n Helper for Rails Menu and keyboard shortcut for internationalizing strings in Rails templates.
Simple at the moment, but useful to anyone who might want to learn how to write a gedit plugin to manipulate selected strings.
https://github.com/ndbroadbent/gedit_i18n_helper</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Punished for Breaking Your Software Tests</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/11/12/get-attacked-for-breaking-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 09:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/11/12/get-attacked-for-breaking-software/</guid>
      <description>At work, we use software called Atlassian Bamboo. It does CI (continuous integration) for us, so whenever a developer updates the code, it will run all of the software&amp;rsquo;s tests, and makes sure everything still works.
We had a USB Missile launcher lying around, and I thought it could be put to good use. So now, whenever a developer commits a change that breaks a test, he gets shot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RFID apartment lock (&amp; iPhone app)</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/11/05/octopus-card-door-lock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 20:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/11/05/octopus-card-door-lock/</guid>
      <description>Octopus cards in Hong Kong can be used to purchase almost anything, such as groceries, McDonalds, and public transport. Since everyone has one, a lot of apartments are using them for access control.
One of my first projects after moving back to Hong Kong was installing an electronic lock on my apartment door. My door can be now be unlocked with an Octopus RFID card, iPhone app, or over the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My attempt at an embossed metal box from beverage can</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/11/05/my-attempt-at-an-embossed-metal-box-from-beverage-can/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 15:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/11/05/my-attempt-at-an-embossed-metal-box-from-beverage-can/</guid>
      <description>I was inspired by a makezine.com article I was reading this evening, and decided to follow a tutorial to make an embossed box out of an aluminium can. I haven&amp;rsquo;t done anything creative for a long time, and I really enjoyed it.
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if sanding the outside of the can is completely necessary, since its only visible on the inside of the box. Also, a ballpoint pen isn&amp;rsquo;t the best tool to use, since it leaves blue ink everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grooveshark - Set Current Song as Browser Title</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/11/04/grooveshark-set-current-song-as-browser-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2010 19:07:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/11/04/grooveshark-set-current-song-as-browser-title/</guid>
      <description>I like Grooveshark. Its like last.fm, but you can choose the songs &amp;amp; albums you want to play. I would like to get a subscription one day, but I&amp;rsquo;m not sure when the RIAA is planning their attack, so maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll hold off for now :)
In the meantime, I was dissapointed that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see which song was currently playing in the browser title. So heres a greasemonkey script to do just that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to use l1merain but it doesn&#39;t work?</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/11/01/trying-to-use-l1merain-but-it-doesnt-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 14:26:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/11/01/trying-to-use-l1merain-but-it-doesnt-work/</guid>
      <description>You are trying to use l1merain to jailbreak on windows xp, but your iPhone doesn&amp;rsquo;t take it.. You should see a green rain drop if the jailbreaking process is successful, but you just see the apple icon.
What you need to do is press CTRL+SHIFT+ESC. Sort by &amp;lsquo;Image Name&amp;rsquo;. Then end these processes: &amp;lsquo;iPodService&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;iTunes&amp;rsquo;.
Your jailbreak should now work fine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make &#39;git status&#39; put filepaths into numbered variables</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/10/29/more-git-shortcuts-filepaths-in-bash-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2010 22:31:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/10/29/more-git-shortcuts-filepaths-in-bash-variables/</guid>
      <description>I like my shortcuts for git (ie. &amp;lsquo;gst&amp;rsquo; for &amp;lsquo;git status&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;gca&amp;rsquo; for &amp;lsquo;git commit -a -m&amp;rsquo;, etc.) But I wanted more, so I thought it would be nice if I could somehow create &amp;lsquo;shortcuts&amp;rsquo; to the filepaths of modified files whenever I run &amp;lsquo;git status&amp;rsquo;. I created a function to export the paths of each modified file into numbered environment variables, and it has really sped up my workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search and replace in multiple files on linux with bash, egrep, sed function</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/10/26/search-and-replace-in-multiple-files-on-linux-with-bash-egrep-sed-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2010 18:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/10/26/search-and-replace-in-multiple-files-on-linux-with-bash-egrep-sed-function/</guid>
      <description>Heres a simple function to add to your shell if you ever want to replace a string in multiple files at once. It ignores everything in .git, otherwise you get &amp;lsquo;bad index file sha1 signature&amp;rsquo; errors.
function gsed () { if [ -z &amp;quot;$3&amp;quot; ] then echo &amp;quot;== Usage: gsed search_string replace_string [path]&amp;quot; else egrep --exclude-dir=.git -lRZ &amp;quot;$1&amp;quot; $3 | xargs -0 -l sed -i -e &amp;quot;s/$1/$2/g&amp;quot; fi }  Add it to the bottom of ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to preserve indentation in wordpress [sourcecode] tags</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/10/19/how-to-keep-indentation-in-wordpress-sourcecode-tags/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 20:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/10/19/how-to-keep-indentation-in-wordpress-sourcecode-tags/</guid>
      <description>Dont use the visual editor. Copy the code into your &amp;lsquo;HTML&amp;rsquo; view and it will preserve indentation. Copy it into &amp;lsquo;Visual&amp;rsquo; view and your code will be all left-aligned&amp;hellip;
Examples:
Code pasted in &amp;lsquo;Visual&amp;rsquo; View
&amp;lt;indent&amp;gt; &amp;lt;indent&amp;gt; &amp;lt;indent&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/indent&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/indent&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/indent&amp;gt;  Code pasted in &amp;lsquo;HTML&amp;rsquo; View
&amp;lt;indent&amp;gt; &amp;lt;indent&amp;gt; &amp;lt;indent&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/indent&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/indent&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/indent&amp;gt;  YMMV, I guess, but this is what works for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use bundler with multiple Gemfiles in plugins / extensions</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/10/19/how-to-use-bundler-with-plugins-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2010 20:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/10/19/how-to-use-bundler-with-plugins-extensions/</guid>
      <description>Bundler makes it very easy to point to a gem folder on your system, and I definitely recommend this approach a lot more. The plugin can be a gem that we can just require, and it can specify its own dependencies in its .gemspec file.
But if you really don&amp;rsquo;t want your plugin to be a gem, for whatever reason, then read on&amp;hellip;
If we are developing a Spree extension, or a Retrospectiva extension, or a Fat Free CRM plugin, we might sometimes need a way to require the gems in multiple Gemfiles, but Bundler doesn&amp;rsquo;t cater for this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure SMTP - SMTP Error: Could not connect to SMTP host.</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/10/07/configure-wordpress-smtp-error-could-not-connect-to-smtp-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 18:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/10/07/configure-wordpress-smtp-error-could-not-connect-to-smtp-host/</guid>
      <description>If you are trying to configure your wordpress installation to send email from your gmail account:  Install the &amp;lsquo;Configure SMTP&amp;rsquo; plugin, and check the &amp;lsquo;Send e-mail via GMail?&amp;rsquo; box. Send a test email to make sure everything is working.  You might get the error message &amp;ldquo;SMTP Error: Could not connect to SMTP host.&amp;rdquo;  You just need to open port 465 on your firewall. You might need to ask your hosting provider / system administrator to do this for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSpec tasks on Rails 3</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/09/25/rspec-tasks-on-rails-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2010 19:51:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/09/25/rspec-tasks-on-rails-3/</guid>
      <description>Problem: uninitialized constant RSpec::Rake
Solution:
You are using rails 3 (and rspec 2), and trying to define a custom rake task with Spec::Rake::SpecTask.new
Instead, do:
RSpec::Core::RakeTask.new(:spec) do |t| ...  and make sure to change:
t.spec_files = FileList[&amp;#39;spec/**/*_spec.rb&amp;#39;]  to
t.pattern = &amp;#39;spec/**/*_spec.rb&amp;#39;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wimp.com rss feed</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/08/05/wimp-com-rss-feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 21:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/08/05/wimp-com-rss-feed/</guid>
      <description>I found out about http://www.wimp.com last year, and have been watching their daily videos ever since. Its a simple website that offers 5 or 6 daily videos on a range of topics, such as science, comedy and innovation. And thats all there is. No bells and whistles, just a daily list of 5 videos. The videos are awesome, but I always wanted to watch them with google reader via rss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to upgrade git on legacy Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/08/04/how-to-upgrade-git-on-legacy-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 23:28:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/08/04/how-to-upgrade-git-on-legacy-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>Follow these steps to get git 1.7 + on ubuntu 9.10 or less. (10.04 comes with the latest version)
sudo apt-get install libcurl4-dev # (for new http[s] support) cd /tmp wget http://kernel.org/pub/software/scm/git/git-1.7.2.1.tar.gz tar -xf git-1.7.2.1.tar.gz cd git-1.7.2.1/ ./configure make sudo make install ln -nfs /usr/bin/git /usr/local/bin/git  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm on embedded systems</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/06/26/last-fm-on-embedded-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/06/26/last-fm-on-embedded-systems/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finished most of the work I&amp;rsquo;m going to do on my shell.fm ruby server. Its written on sinatra + jquery + jquery-ui (so, a lot of ajax calls). It also requires my custom shell.fm fork if you want the volume control to work.
You can find my shell.fm fork here: http://github.com/ndbroadbent/shell-fm
and the shell.fm sinatra server is here: http://github.com/ndbroadbent/shell-fm_sinatra
By the way, this post is about an embedded linux system that plays last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&amp;#039;t override core Rails methods</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/28/dont-override-core-rails-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2010 14:55:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/28/dont-override-core-rails-methods/</guid>
      <description>Every programmer makes mistakes.. But every so often though, you make those mistakes that really mess things up. I just made two of them, and feel like a right n00b.
Both mistakes simply involved overwriting ActiveRecord methods. The first time, I made an &amp;lsquo;update&amp;rsquo; method in my model. And just recently, I realized that I had made a named_scope called &amp;lsquo;new&amp;rsquo; for another model.
NEVER use method names such as &amp;lsquo;create&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;update&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;new&amp;rsquo;, or &amp;lsquo;destroy&amp;rsquo; in ANY of your models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>git shortcuts</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/21/git-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 13:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/21/git-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>It seems that for every single git repository I create, I just want to be able to run &amp;ldquo;git push&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;git pull&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;git pull origin master&amp;rdquo; just gets annoying after a while. In case I forget how to do this again, this is all it takes (provided you already have an &amp;lsquo;origin&amp;rsquo; remote configured):
git config branch.master.remote origin git config branch.master.merge refs/heads/master  Other useful git shortcut that I literally use everyday (add them to the bottom of ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a favicon.ico with GIMP</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/20/how-to-create-a-favicon-ico-with-gimp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 13:19:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/20/how-to-create-a-favicon-ico-with-gimp/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Theres an easier way to do this here: http://www.htmlcenter.com/blog/creating-a-favicon-for-your-website/.
http://linuxproblem.org/art_19.html
By Mathias Kettner :
You need an image file that GIMP can open (PNG, GIF, etc.). And you need the command line tool ppmtowinicon from the netpbm-tools (on SuSE you have to have installed the package netpbm). Now perform the following actions:
 Open your image with GIMP. If your image is not a square then resize the canvas with GIMP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>blueberry pi</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/14/blueberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2010 11:02:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/14/blueberry-pi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scanning lots of photos at once with GIMP on Ubuntu Linux</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/13/scanning-lots-of-photos-at-once/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 22:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/13/scanning-lots-of-photos-at-once/</guid>
      <description>I needed a way to scan a lot of photos at once. I was going to write a GIMP plugin to extract out multiple images from a single scanned image of 3 or 4 photos, and then rotate them automatically. But as always, someone had already beat me to it :)
See this forum on GimpTalk for the original script.
(The only problem I had is that the Deskew plugin for GIMP is located on a website whose server seems to be permanently offline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YoutubeJukebox</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/13/youtubejukebox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 17:46:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/13/youtubejukebox/</guid>
      <description>http://github.com/ndbroadbent/youtube_jukebox
A ruby script that downloads youtube videos, converts them to mp3, and plays them in a vlc playlist as they are processed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>obscure jqGrid API notes</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/06/obscure-jqgrid-api-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2010 15:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/05/06/obscure-jqgrid-api-notes/</guid>
      <description>If you are using an older version of jqGrid because it comes nicely wrapped up in the jquery-grid-rails-plugin, keep in mind that all the demo code is written with the new API introduced in version 3.6. Fortunately, most of the demo code can still be reused with our version of jqGrid (3.5). Just get rid of any &amp;ldquo;jqGrid(&amp;rsquo; ****** &amp;lsquo;)&amp;rdquo; function wrappers, and everything should work fine. (I find this easier to do than rewriting the rails plugin for the new version)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jqgrid on Spree</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/30/jqgrid-on-spree/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 17:22:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/30/jqgrid-on-spree/</guid>
      <description>Been a fan of jqgrid for quite some time, but wasn&amp;rsquo;t looking forward to the struggle of getting it to work with Rails.
Thankfully, someones already done it for me: http://www.2dconcept.com/jquery-grid-rails-plugin
It did take a little while to debug some things that were going wrong, though. Firebug was giving me the error: $.jgrid.formatter is undefined. After some digging around, I realized that no jqgrid locale files were being loaded.
By default, Spree has its i18n locale set to &amp;ldquo;en-US&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm Player - Project Videos</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/project-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 11:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/project-videos/</guid>
      <description>My Compaq Evo T20 running tinycore linux, playing shell.fm, displaying track info via lcd4linux on a Pertelian X2o40 USB LCD display.

 
Uses music software Reaper to play audio and generate MIDI events. Midi events are sent to the &#39;output&#39; of MIDI Yoke, which patches them to a software emulated MIDI input. Used the MIDIOX COM wrapper with Visual Basic, to monitor the MIDI Yoke input and trigger http downloads on certain MIDI note events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use a bluetooth headset on Ubuntu 9.10 &#43;</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/how-to-use-a-bluetooth-headset-on-ubuntu-9-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 10:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/how-to-use-a-bluetooth-headset-on-ubuntu-9-10/</guid>
      <description>I found a little bluetooth headset at work, and wanted to play audio through it from my laptop. It turns out that nowadays, Ubuntu actually makes this really easy.
I found a guide written for Ubuntu 9.04 on this forum post, but Ubuntu 9.10 now does most of the work for you. (Steps 15 through 27 are still used in this guide, so credit to HyRax1 from forums.overclockers.com.au for the original tutorial)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fireworks display in time to music.</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/25/fireworks-display-in-time-to-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 14:06:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/25/fireworks-display-in-time-to-music/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a REAPER license for a year or 2 now. Get rid of Logic Pro and Protools, REAPER is the most awesome music creation software I have ever used. I love the unparalleled flexibility to make it do whatever you can imagine.
I just followed this extremely helpful tutorial by Dave Hayes  to get REAPER running on Ubuntu with wineasio. And now, I am in the middle of researching midi plugins that can trigger shell or network events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking DSP-420 LCD displays</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/25/my-job-is-sweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 13:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/25/my-job-is-sweet/</guid>
      <description>I recently found a bunch ofDSP-420 LCD displays, like the ones that you see on POS terminals in grocery stores. After a fruitless battle with the proprietary protocol of an LED wallboard (that I also found at work :) ), it was good to find so much protocol documentation on these little displays. I had it up and running within a few hours, displaying the artist, title and track length from shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pertelian X2040, lcd4linux, shell-fm</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/20/pertelian-x2040-lcd4linux-shell-fm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 13:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/20/pertelian-x2040-lcd4linux-shell-fm/</guid>
      <description>I received my Pertelian X2040, and had a bit of trouble getting it work on my 64bit Ubuntu machine. The characters were getting all mixed up. I gave up on my 64bit machine and decided to focus my efforts on the T20 running tinycore.
To get lcd4linux running on tinycore with any lcd screen, you need the dbus, usbutils and usb-serial packages installed.
At first, lcd4linux was asking me for mysql, and then sqlite, and those are pretty hefty packages for a little thin client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next project!</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/15/next-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 23:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/15/next-project/</guid>
      <description>So I have practically finished the last.fm player. Its running as I type this, and the sinatra server running on the machine is keeping me up to date with the tracks that are playing. But I&amp;rsquo;m not quite finished with this little project yet.
At work, I found an Advatel TCD226C LED Wallboard. It is a single line, 26 character LED display, that can communicate over RS232. The only problem is that the protocol is proprietary and the manufacturer isnt going to budge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Compaq Evo T20 works</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/15/it-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 22:22:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/15/it-works/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finished the software research stage of my Compaq Evo T20 experiments. I have settled on the Tinycore 2.7 distribution. So I now have a 300MHz thin client that:
 can connect to a wired or wireless network. can play audio through its onboard sound device. has the required libraries to run MPD (music player daemon) and shell.fm (minimal console application for streaming last.fm stations.) can run Ruby 1.8.7, rubygems, rails, sinatra, etc (Ruby 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compaq Evo T20 projects</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/08/compaq-evo-t20-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 13:51:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/08/compaq-evo-t20-projects/</guid>
      <description>Compaq Evo T20s are fun. I have a few that I&amp;rsquo;m using for various projects. I plan to set one up as a RFID controlled alarm/door lock system. Its running Damn Small Linux using ruby, rubygems and sinatra packages that I compiled myself.
Karl Mowatt-Wilson&amp;rsquo;s tutorials have been a huge help with flashing the T20s with linux images, as well as the open-evot20 site.
I wrote a K8055 USB Ruby C wrapper for the K8055 USB interface experiment board (bought from here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This blog should have been started a long time ago</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/07/this-blog-should-have-been-started-a-long-time-ago/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2010 13:30:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/07/this-blog-should-have-been-started-a-long-time-ago/</guid>
      <description>I am indebted to the collective Internet. My workflow mostly consists of &amp;ldquo;problem -&amp;gt; google -&amp;gt; forum/blog -&amp;gt; solution&amp;rdquo;.
After years of stealing answers from other peoples forum posts and blogs, I finally have my own place to share and hopefully help other people out. This will be a scrapbook of errors, headaches, solutions, and whatever other random stuff I feel like sharing with you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>