<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Made By Nathan</title>
    <link>https://madebynathan.com/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Made By Nathan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 04:07:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://madebynathan.com/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing 1,700 Resistors in a Ring Binder</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/posts/2022-10-30-e24-resistor-pack-ring-binder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 04:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/posts/2022-10-30-e24-resistor-pack-ring-binder/</guid>
      <description>I used a ring binder and card sleeves to organize 1,700 through-hole resistors.
You can use this PDF to make your own ring binder:
 
 Download E24_Resistor_Kit_Folder.pdf Liquid and SCSS that was used to generate the PDF   The template code and generated PDF document are released under the MIT license. You can find a copy of the MIT license at the bottom of this page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating my Kitchen Rangehood Fan and Light</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/posts/2022-09-30-automating-my-kitchen-rangehood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 10:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/posts/2022-09-30-automating-my-kitchen-rangehood/</guid>
      <description>I originally posted this write-up on the Home Assistant Community Forums. I thought I would post it here as well, since I haven&amp;rsquo;t written anything on this blog for a while. I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting more serious about Home Automation lately, so I might start writing some more blog posts and making a few videos.
 I figured out how to control the light and fan in the rangehood above my stove.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Learned While Making a Game With React Native</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/posts/2018-02-12-what-i-learned-while-making-a-game-with-react-native/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 01:34:40 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/posts/2018-02-12-what-i-learned-while-making-a-game-with-react-native/</guid>
      <description>I used React Native to build a cross-platform game for iOS, Android, Windows, and the web. SudoBlock is a cross between Sudoku, jigsaw puzzles, and Tetris.
You can find SudoBlock on the web, App Store, Google Play, and the Microsoft Store.

React Native only supports iOS and Android, but I used react-native-web for the browser, and react-native-windows for Windows desktop and phone. The UWP app can also run on Xbox One and HoloLens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Microwave</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2013/07/10/raspberry-pi-powered-microwave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 23:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2013/07/10/raspberry-pi-powered-microwave/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, I was inspired by this post on Reddit, titled: Food items should have QR codes that instruct the microwave exactly what to do. Like high for 2 minutes, let stand 1 minute, medium 1 minutes..
I thought this was a pretty cool idea, and that it would be a fun project for a Raspberry Pi. I agreed with the people who thought using UPC barcodes would be better, since products already have them, so I went with a barcode scanner + online product database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatically change iPhone wallpaper every 30 minutes</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2011/07/20/automatically-change-iphone-wallpaper-every-30-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2011 16:27:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2011/07/20/automatically-change-iphone-wallpaper-every-30-minutes/</guid>
      <description>NOTE: This is only for jailbroken iPhones.
I love finding awesome wallpapers on reddit. My Ubuntu desktop cycles through my wallpaper collection with a program called Cortina, and I wanted my iPhone to do the same.
So I wrote a very simple script and a launchd plist that runs the script every 30 minutes. If you want to set this up for your jailbroken iPhone, all you need is SSH and a collection of images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repurposed pressure gauge - Bathroom door indicator</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2011/04/30/repurposed-pressure-gauge-as-bathroom-indicator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 15:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2011/04/30/repurposed-pressure-gauge-as-bathroom-indicator/</guid>
      <description>I turned an old brass pressure gauge into a vacant/engaged indicator for our bathroom. The needle is a hacked ammeter, and the metal slide lock on the other side of the door switches it on.
(Inspired by this analog bandwidth meter.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avatar Harmony - Sync your profile pics</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2011/04/25/avatar-harmony-sync-your-profile-pics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 17:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2011/04/25/avatar-harmony-sync-your-profile-pics/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a tiny web application called &amp;lsquo;Avatar Harmony&amp;rsquo;.
You can sign in with twitter or facebook, add your Gravatar login details, and the app will automatically sync your profile pics across each of your accounts.
It can sync avatars in the following directions:
 Facebook =&amp;gt; Twitter Facebook =&amp;gt; Gravatar Twitter =&amp;gt; Gravatar Gravatar =&amp;gt; Twitter  Unfortunately, the Facebook Graph API doesn&#39;t let us update profile pics at the moment, but I&#39;ll keep looking around for a solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Notifier</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2011/03/19/weather-notifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 15:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2011/03/19/weather-notifier/</guid>
      <description>This is just a little idea I had on the bus.
Outside my apartment, I have a bucket for umbrellas.
A program checks the local weather on weather.com from time to time. If there&#39;s any chance of rain, it switches on the lights installed in the bucket.
So when I walk out the door, I know whether or not I should take an umbrella to work.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Calvin &amp; Hobbes RSS feed (with embedded images)</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2011/01/29/daily-calvin-hobbes-rss-feed-with-embedded-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2011 08:26:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2011/01/29/daily-calvin-hobbes-rss-feed-with-embedded-images/</guid>
      <description>Yahoo Pipes is fantastic. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t a big fan of yahoo in the past, but their pipes service is amazing. Its great for sprucing up a not-so-well implemented RSS feed, and lets you create feeds from virtually anything on the web.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a daily Calvin and Hobbes RSS feed that parses the comic image from the linked page, and drops it in the feed itself. Perfect for Google Reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo iPhone app - Apartment automation</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/12/28/demo-iphone-app-apartment-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 18:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/12/28/demo-iphone-app-apartment-automation/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/ndbroadbent/ios_flat_10c
This is the little app I wrote to control my apartment. Its not going to be much use to anyone by itself, but as it says on the github page:
You could use this as a demo app to help you learn about:
 InAppSettingsKit  Configure settings from within an iPhone app.   ASI HTTP library  Sending HTTP GET and POST requests with form data.   Cloning the ‘slide to unlock’ feature from the iPhone lock screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More home automation..</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/12/27/more-home-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2010 16:29:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/12/27/more-home-automation/</guid>
      <description>My hall light turns on for 15 minutes if it&amp;rsquo;s past 10pm and I unlock my door with an octopus card or iPhone.

Its just a 12v relay (rated at 240V/30A), and some cat-5 to the thin client PC. All happens to fit perfectly inside the light switch.
Next up, automatic plant watering &amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Punished for Breaking Your Software Tests</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/11/12/get-attacked-for-breaking-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 09:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/11/12/get-attacked-for-breaking-software/</guid>
      <description>At work, we use software called Atlassian Bamboo. It does CI (continuous integration) for us, so whenever a developer updates the code, it will run all of the software&amp;rsquo;s tests, and makes sure everything still works.
We had a USB Missile launcher lying around, and I thought it could be put to good use. So now, whenever a developer commits a change that breaks a test, he gets shot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RFID apartment lock (&amp; iPhone app)</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/11/05/octopus-card-door-lock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 20:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/11/05/octopus-card-door-lock/</guid>
      <description>Octopus cards in Hong Kong can be used to purchase almost anything, such as groceries, McDonalds, and public transport. Since everyone has one, a lot of apartments are using them for access control.
One of my first projects after moving back to Hong Kong was installing an electronic lock on my apartment door. My door can be now be unlocked with an Octopus RFID card, iPhone app, or over the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>wimp.com rss feed</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/08/05/wimp-com-rss-feed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2010 21:12:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/08/05/wimp-com-rss-feed/</guid>
      <description>I found out about http://www.wimp.com last year, and have been watching their daily videos ever since. Its a simple website that offers 5 or 6 daily videos on a range of topics, such as science, comedy and innovation. And thats all there is. No bells and whistles, just a daily list of 5 videos. The videos are awesome, but I always wanted to watch them with google reader via rss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm on embedded systems</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/06/26/last-fm-on-embedded-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/06/26/last-fm-on-embedded-systems/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finished most of the work I&amp;rsquo;m going to do on my shell.fm ruby server. Its written on sinatra + jquery + jquery-ui (so, a lot of ajax calls). It also requires my custom shell.fm fork if you want the volume control to work.
You can find my shell.fm fork here: http://github.com/ndbroadbent/shell-fm
and the shell.fm sinatra server is here: http://github.com/ndbroadbent/shell-fm_sinatra
By the way, this post is about an embedded linux system that plays last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm Player - Project Videos</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/project-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 11:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/project-videos/</guid>
      <description>My Compaq Evo T20 running tinycore linux, playing shell.fm, displaying track info via lcd4linux on a Pertelian X2o40 USB LCD display.

 
Uses music software Reaper to play audio and generate MIDI events. Midi events are sent to the &#39;output&#39; of MIDI Yoke, which patches them to a software emulated MIDI input. Used the MIDIOX COM wrapper with Visual Basic, to monitor the MIDI Yoke input and trigger http downloads on certain MIDI note events.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>