<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Made by Nathan</title>
    <link>https://madebynathan.com/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Made by Nathan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 23:51:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://madebynathan.com/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Microwave</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2013/07/10/raspberry-pi-powered-microwave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2013 23:51:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2013/07/10/raspberry-pi-powered-microwave/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, I was inspired by this post on Reddit, titled: Food items should have QR codes that instruct the microwave exactly what to do. Like high for 2 minutes, let stand 1 minute, medium 1 minutes..
I thought this was a pretty cool idea, and that it would be a fun project for a Raspberry Pi. I agreed with the people who thought using UPC barcodes would be better, since products already have them, so I went with a barcode scanner + online product database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SCM Breeze</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2011/10/19/git-shortcuts-like-youve-never-seen-before/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 01:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2011/10/19/git-shortcuts-like-youve-never-seen-before/</guid>
      <description>SCM Breeze is a set of shell scripts (for bash and zsh) that make it easier to use git. It integrates with your shell to give you numbered file shortcuts, a repository index with tab completion, and a community driven collection of useful SCM functions.
Disclaimer: git is currently the only supported SCM. I&amp;rsquo;ve kept the project&amp;rsquo;s name open because it won&amp;rsquo;t be difficult to port it for other SCMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repurposed pressure gauge - Bathroom door indicator</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2011/04/30/repurposed-pressure-gauge-as-bathroom-indicator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2011 15:44:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2011/04/30/repurposed-pressure-gauge-as-bathroom-indicator/</guid>
      <description>I turned an old brass pressure gauge into a vacant/engaged indicator for our bathroom. The needle is a hacked ammeter, and the metal slide lock on the other side of the door switches it on.
(Inspired by this analog bandwidth meter.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avatar Harmony - Sync your profile pics</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2011/04/25/avatar-harmony-sync-your-profile-pics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2011 17:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2011/04/25/avatar-harmony-sync-your-profile-pics/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written a tiny web application called &amp;lsquo;Avatar Harmony&amp;rsquo;.
You can sign in with twitter or facebook, add your Gravatar login details, and the app will automatically sync your profile pics across each of your accounts.
It can sync avatars in the following directions:
 Facebook =&amp;gt; Twitter Facebook =&amp;gt; Gravatar Twitter =&amp;gt; Gravatar Gravatar =&amp;gt; Twitter  Unfortunately, the Facebook Graph API doesn&#39;t let us update profile pics at the moment, but I&#39;ll keep looking around for a solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weather Notifier</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2011/03/19/weather-notifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2011 15:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2011/03/19/weather-notifier/</guid>
      <description>This is just a little idea I had on the bus.
Outside my apartment, I have a bucket for umbrellas.
A program checks the local weather on weather.com from time to time. If there&#39;s any chance of rain, it switches on the lights installed in the bucket.
So when I walk out the door, I know whether or not I should take an umbrella to work.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo iPhone app - Apartment automation</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/12/28/demo-iphone-app-apartment-automation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 18:21:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/12/28/demo-iphone-app-apartment-automation/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/ndbroadbent/ios_flat_10c
This is the little app I wrote to control my apartment. Its not going to be much use to anyone by itself, but as it says on the github page:
You could use this as a demo app to help you learn about:  InAppSettingsKit  Configure settings from within an iPhone app.   ASI HTTP library  Sending HTTP GET and POST requests with form data.   Cloning the ‘slide to unlock’ feature from the iPhone lock screen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS JB tweak - Replace operator with current prepaid balance</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/12/26/ios-tweak-replace-operator-with-current-prepaid-balance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2010 16:42:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/12/26/ios-tweak-replace-operator-with-current-prepaid-balance/</guid>
      <description>https://github.com/ndbroadbent/ios_replace_operator_with_balance
Replace Operator on jailbroken iOS 4.x with current prepaid balance. Specifically written for PCCW in Hong Kong, with an AT+CUSD command of “##122#”.
An extension to Fake-Operator
Credit to this site for the source code of sendmodem.
Install
Download the .deb package from the ‘Downloads’ page on github, and install with $ dpkg -i &amp;lt;&amp;lt; package &amp;gt;&amp;gt;.deb
How it works
Package contains an executable binary that sends an AT USSD command to the carrier, which returns the balance message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Punished for Breaking Your Software Tests</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/11/12/get-attacked-for-breaking-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2010 09:38:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/11/12/get-attacked-for-breaking-software/</guid>
      <description>At work, we use software called Atlassian Bamboo. It does CI (continuous integration) for us, so whenever a developer updates the code, it will run all of the software&amp;rsquo;s tests, and makes sure everything still works.
We had a USB Missile launcher lying around, and I thought it could be put to good use. So now, whenever a developer commits a change that breaks a test, he gets shot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RFID apartment lock (&amp; iPhone app)</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/11/05/octopus-card-door-lock/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 20:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/11/05/octopus-card-door-lock/</guid>
      <description>Octopus cards in Hong Kong can be used to purchase almost anything, such as groceries, McDonalds, and public transport. Since everyone has one, a lot of apartments are using them for access control.
One of my first projects after moving back to Hong Kong was installing an electronic lock on my apartment door. My door can be now be unlocked with an Octopus RFID card, iPhone app, or over the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My attempt at an embossed metal box from beverage can</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/11/05/my-attempt-at-an-embossed-metal-box-from-beverage-can/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 15:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/11/05/my-attempt-at-an-embossed-metal-box-from-beverage-can/</guid>
      <description>I was inspired by a makezine.com article I was reading this evening, and decided to follow a tutorial to make an embossed box out of an aluminium can. I haven&amp;rsquo;t done anything creative for a long time, and I really enjoyed it.
I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if sanding the outside of the can is completely necessary, since its only visible on the inside of the box. Also, a ballpoint pen isn&amp;rsquo;t the best tool to use, since it leaves blue ink everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm Player - Project Videos</title>
      <link>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/project-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 11:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://madebynathan.com/2010/04/29/project-videos/</guid>
      <description>My Compaq Evo T20 running tinycore linux, playing shell.fm, displaying track info via lcd4linux on a Pertelian X2o40 USB LCD display.

 
Uses music software Reaper to play audio and generate MIDI events. Midi events are sent to the &#39;output&#39; of MIDI Yoke, which patches them to a software emulated MIDI input. Used the MIDIOX COM wrapper with Visual Basic, to monitor the MIDI Yoke input and trigger http downloads on certain MIDI note events.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>