<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Administration on Made by Nathan</title>
    <link>http://madebynathan.com/tags/administration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Administration on Made by Nathan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 12:55:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://madebynathan.com/tags/administration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>capistrano_colors has been merged into capistrano</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/11/08/capistrano_colors-has-been-merged-into-capistrano/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 12:55:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/11/08/capistrano_colors-has-been-merged-into-capistrano/</guid>
      <description>capistrano_colors has been merged into capistrano. If you update capistrano to version 2.13.5, you will no longer need to include capistrano_colors in your Gemfile.Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to also remove require &#39;capistrano_colors&#39; from config/deploy.rb.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve been using capistrano without the capistrano_colors gem, well, you&amp;rsquo;ve been missing out! Your logs will now be nicely formatted and colored by default, like this:
However, if you happen to be a big fan of black &amp;amp; white logs, you can just add disable_log_formatters to config/deploy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to start a Google Group for a git project</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/09/19/how-to-start-a-google-group-for-a-git-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 12:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/09/19/how-to-start-a-google-group-for-a-git-project/</guid>
      <description>GitHub is a great way to manage code for an open source project, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide any way to send a message to all of your watchers. This can be necessary whenever you make certain changes to your application. For example, I recently merged a pull request in Errbit that requires users to run a Rake task next time they update the code. I had no way of notifying our users, so I decided to create a Google Group mailing list for these kinds of notifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling one-off tasks with &#39;at&#39;</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2012/02/25/scheduling-one-off-tasks-with-at-/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 17:00:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2012/02/25/scheduling-one-off-tasks-with-at-/</guid>
      <description>You might be familiar with the cron job scheduler, which is great for repeating tasks. But when you want to schedule a command to only run once in the future, the at command is what you are looking for.
In my case, I was updating a plugin for our Thoughtworks Mingle instance, but the update wasn&amp;rsquo;t hugely important. Many of our staff rely on Mingle for their work, and restarting it takes it offline for a few minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>