<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lcd4linux on Nathan Broadbent</title>
    <link>http://madebynathan.com/tags/lcd4linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lcd4linux on Nathan Broadbent</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:30:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://madebynathan.com/tags/lcd4linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Last.fm on embedded systems</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/06/26/last-fm-on-embedded-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2010 00:30:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/06/26/last-fm-on-embedded-systems/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finished most of the work I&amp;rsquo;m going to do on my shell.fm ruby server. Its written on sinatra + jquery + jquery-ui (so, a lot of ajax calls). It also requires my custom shell.fm fork if you want the volume control to work.
You can find my shell.fm fork here: http://github.com/ndbroadbent/shell-fm
and the shell.fm sinatra server is here: http://github.com/ndbroadbent/shell-fm_sinatra
By the way, this post is about an embedded linux system that plays last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking DSP-420 LCD displays</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/25/my-job-is-sweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2010 13:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/25/my-job-is-sweet/</guid>
      <description>I recently found a bunch ofDSP-420 LCD displays, like the ones that you see on POS terminals in grocery stores. After a fruitless battle with the proprietary protocol of an LED wallboard (that I also found at work :) ), it was good to find so much protocol documentation on these little displays. I had it up and running within a few hours, displaying the artist, title and track length from shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pertelian X2040, lcd4linux, shell-fm</title>
      <link>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/20/pertelian-x2040-lcd4linux-shell-fm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2010 13:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://madebynathan.com/2010/04/20/pertelian-x2040-lcd4linux-shell-fm/</guid>
      <description>I received my Pertelian X2040, and had a bit of trouble getting it work on my 64bit Ubuntu machine. The characters were getting all mixed up. I gave up on my 64bit machine and decided to focus my efforts on the T20 running tinycore.
To get lcd4linux running on tinycore with any lcd screen, you need the dbus, usbutils and usb-serial packages installed.
At first, lcd4linux was asking me for mysql, and then sqlite, and those are pretty hefty packages for a little thin client.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>